# **AKINOLA FEMI (Full stack developer)**

Lagos City, Lagos Nigeria +234-9136427420 akinolafemi573@gmail.com

## **SUMMARY**

I'm a seasoned Full Stack Developer with expertise in both front-end and back-end development. My goal is to become associated with a company where I can utilize my skills and gain further experience while enhancing the company's productivity and reputation.

## **EDUCATION**

# Digital World Tech Academy, Lagos Nigeria

January - June 2024 | Software Engineering

#### **RELEVANT COURSEWORK:**

Systems Administration | Website Design | User Experience | Client-Side Development | Vectors & Illustration | Responsive Design | Database Administration | Web Page Programming

Certificate: Full Stack Professional Certificates January 2024 – June 2024

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Code Alpha**

India Lucknow U.P (remote) | June 2024 - current

- Translating Figma designs into pixel-perfect interactive web interfaces using HTML, CSS,
  JavaScript and React.
- Actively contributing to the development of key features using HTML, React.Js and Styled-Components Kept work area organized and clutter free.

## **Digital World Tech Academy Ikorodu Lagos**

Internship Instructor | July 2024 - Current

Implemented new responsive, mobile-first approach which increased mobile traffic by 20% within the first month of project.

- Contributing to the team's overall growth by sharing valuable resources and learning materials related to front-end developmentand and helping them understand the key concepts.
- Implemented visual aids and technology-based learning tools to support student learning
- Monitored student improvement, productivity, attendance and followed up on absent.

# **SKILLS**

\*FRONTEND:- HTML, CSS, Tailwind, Sass, JavaScript, React.

\*BACKEND:- Node JS, Mongodb.

\*OTHER:- Search Engine optimization (SEO), Responsive Web Development (RWD). \*Version Control:- Github and Git, Postman and Thunder Client.

\*SOFT SkILLs:- Problem Solving | Teamwork | Communication | Critical Thinking | Collaboration | Timeless.

## **PROJECT**

My portfolio website: URL: akinolafemi.com.ng

Description:

Timeframe: 3 days to design from scratch -number of pages: 2 (home, and portfolio) -techologies used; HTML, CSS and JavaScript...

## **LANGUAGES**

- English
- Yoruba
- French

# **SOCIAL PROFILE**

LinkedIn: LinkedIn - Profile

Git Hub url: github.com/Famzy077

Facebook, Instagram